so yesterday we talked that we're doing
class two of course three which is
called the plied meditation applied
means use it for something don't just go
in a cave and meditate okay and we were
talking about it was confusing for me
for a long time there's six
preliminaries and there's seven
ingredients okay so it can be confusing
okay six things to do before you
meditate and seven things to do you pay
for humidity right okay so it's for me
it was always confusing so I'm gonna try
to clear a few confuse you more okay six
preliminaries that we talked about in
the first class thanks for the yoga
class a good time and you're a great
teacher by the way tonight we're gonna
talk a lot about teaching meditation and
it's similar to teaching yoga so the
more chances you get to teach the better
teacher you will be okay I teach about a
hundred and eighty days a year when I'm
at the college I teach six classes a day
so I teach a couple hundred classes two
or 300 classes 400 classes every year
and so so high money so try to teach as
much as you can okay every time you get
a chance then teach and with yoga and
meditation you know it stopped a long
time ago that we didn't know yoga you
know like someone came taught us all
yoga and we couldn't teach yoga but now
I think most of the people can teach you
and then you go to a second stage of
teaching where you start teaching each
other for fun
okay and my llama I remember the first
time I went to his class in New York he
I was still at Princeton and I used to
commute to his class and in the end
somebody asked him what's gonna happen
when all the Buddhist when we all become
Buddhist you know what happens then you
know and he said what do you think they
all retired and they sit around and
teach each other cuz it's fun to teach
and they know what the other guy's gonna
say before they say it's okay so it's
like that you can teach the people in
your own Dharma group you know like
Singapore you have a very sweet group
that Jenny Wong built over many years
with her team and so when you get to
where you all know everything which is
called Buddhahood know like if you know
the whole meditation class didn't teach
each other then we do that on d
c---eight or we just rent a room in the
hotel and we all go there and we say who
wants to teach a class and somebody says
I'll teach the class and then you get
experience you get more and more
experience so teach each other
okay practice teaching each other and
encourage each other to teach it's not
really called egotistical you are you
are gaining experience that will be
helpful from when you meet people who
don't know yoga where they don't know
meditation okay so when you're with your
friends like on the way down here we
always stop at the yoga studio in Tucson
they never have a class when we need it
so we don't even ask them for a class we
just rent the room we rent the back room
and we go in and we make noise we played
loud music and and we say who's gonna
teach you know and then somebody teaches
so when you're with your diamond friends
like don't waste the time you know don't
waste doing your yoga every day
and it's you're much more likely to do
it if you get in the habit when you win
you're with your friends don't go out to
dinner don't go to a movie don't talk
about Trump okay I say let's do our
practice let's let's get our practice
done okay and then get your practice
done then you can go out for a huge
dinner guilt-free without guilt and then
the next day you have to do your again
cuz you have a big tummy and so use the
time with your friends to gain
experience in teaching and encourage
each other to teach you know and be
honest with each other you know say that
that was that you promised you wouldn't
do splits and then you do something
worse you know just kidding
give your friends suggestions because
among friends you can be critical right
you can say you know you should talk a
little bit louder or your music should
be Neil Young stop this modern music at
all you know give each other suggestions
okay
and that's a big teaching you learn more
from each other than you do from me okay
but just get in the habit when you're
with your friends have meditate together
do yoga together and rotate who teaches
okay then you get a lot of experience
then when you have to teach a larger
group I think I think DCI teaches yoga
to more new people in the world every
year than any other organization I think
so we do 30,000 people here in the
beginning Yogi's maybe I don't know a
thousand of to 3,000 and our teachers
are good because they we we teach each
other every day
okay so do that alright so here's the
six preliminaries
that we went through yesterday and I
just want to show you where we put the
seven ingredients okay and then you
won't get confused okay so six steps to
start your yoga and one of them has
seven steps okay this is called Georgia
say Georgia Georgia means preliminaries
how to start your meditation practice
and the other is by the way Georgia to
say to took me in six six preliminaries
okay and then en logged in se-young
logged in which literally means the
seven branches of the tree and a bank
branch branch is also called a yin mark
Donka in sanskrit okay like Ashtanga
means eight limbs of yoga Ashtanga
Ashtanga Ashtanga means eight eight
branches i don't like to call them the
eight branches i find it kind of
irritating when people call the seven
the seven limbs and like seven limbs you
know the arms legs few others I guess
boys have more but but I don't know I've
never sounded very good to me it means
ingredients of like a recipe okay
so there's six preliminaries what do you
call seven it's like this six is like
this seven don't ask this to Chinese
people everyone show a different thing
okay
seven
[Music]
seven like that seven what's this one
this is a okay anyways seven ingredients
okay and they go they are tired of the
city they are inside one of the six here
we go here's the six number one create a
beautiful space for your meditation
create a beautiful meditation space and
that's really fun okay that can be
really fun
done don't whine about it's not like
washing dishes okay like enjoy it make a
beautiful space I like it when I visit
my friends and I I can see their
meditation space it's something
beautiful okay so choose a beautiful
make a beautiful place it's a it's a fun
to make a beautiful part of your
apartment where you don't throw your
clothes okay everything else can you can
throw your clothes I have old underwear
everywhere
it's like flowers but that one space is
nice okay number two put forth beautiful
offerings every morning okay Buddha's
like flowers I don't know why okay they
like water they like churros
good if you have a children in your
house okay number three go for refuge
and think about bodhichitta
it just means you can think about the
challenges in your life your work
challenges this is your personal
challenges take refuge which is just
refused desire to say I didn't do
anything
that's all that's refuge that's Kong
King
that's domine - Anita okay forget that I
didn't do anything that's taking refuge
okay
then think about bodhichitta think about
it this way okay don't think I'm gonna
save all living things when I become a
Buddha that's too far away okay
I like the DCI is it's a nice way to say
I will become the best person I can so I
can be a good example for other people
and in that way I will become a human
virus okay when we had class with you
today or we had a lot of classes with
Anatole last week you can see they're
doing their yoga you know they don't
have to say anything you can see all the
impossible things they do they must be
doing something then their virus you
know they don't talk about it they just
do it you can see from when how they
moved there they're doing it probably
okay and that's bodhichitta like I want
to be a virus okay I'm gonna be a good
example for everybody else okay don't
think Bodhisattva everybody to forget it
love a love virus I want to be a love
thank you okay
yeah they used to call them buddy
surface now they call them love virus
all right number four you're supposed to
invite a lot of Angels to your to your
room okay if you get in that habit it's
it's very nice it's very sweet because
I'm not saying you can see them or talk
to them I guess you can after a while
but it's nice to know they're there you
can feel they're there if you invite
them you feel something in the room I
like this custom in Islam during the
prayers yeah we had an imam come and
teach us and they go and he after the
ceremony he asked us any questions we
said why do you go he said I'm talking
to my angels you know every time they
appear to him angels watching over them
so they talk to him
you know watch my back tonight and stuff
like that so invite them and feel them
there okay
that's number four okay number five Suk
Jong say Suk Jong just before you
meditate get a big hit of good karma the
biggest one you can do okay
I know it's like taking your hormones
just before you steroids before you run
Indian then just before you do some
heavy good karma okay and just before
you meditate do some confession clean
clean the dirty stuff from this week
okay and then you're ready to meditate
okay then you have a lot of power to
meditate and you don't have obstacles
okay
you can't possibly confess all the lousy
stuff you did last week it would take
you more time than meditating so just
pick the top two top three I yelled at
my mother you know I didn't pay my taxes
I made fun of John Brady's here stuff
like that okay take the worst ones you
can't think about them and don't get
depressed okay everyone makes mistakes
if you didn't make mistakes you wouldn't
be here just think if you didn't make
mistakes you couldn't come to Diamond
Mountain the reason we're all here is
we're not good people we're not we're
not perfect you know we still have to go
to class and we still have to meditate
okay so I think it's great that we do so
many bad things then we can come to
class okay so just clean the number one
you know you know what they are you
never tell anybody
when you confess you always tell them
number two number three I know you never
really confess the number one bad deeds
except to yourself okay but do it to
yourself
that's called Suk Jong that was number
five number six ask for the blessing of
these holy beings help my mind during
this meditation help my mind during this
it's always good to ask for help from
your Lama it's always good to ask for
help okay
even in your mind okay hey help me um
I'm having a bad day okay help me okay
learn to ask okay what did jesus say if
you don't knock they can't open the door
no one's gonna unlock the door but you
have to know okay so just ask you know I
need I need some help today okay come on
this is what I'm paying you for
I need some help okay now I gave you six
right gasps which one has the seven
ingredients in it number number five
okay Suk Jong Suk Jong so there's gonna
be seven ways to do Suk Jong there's
seven different ways to do Suk Jong okay
unless you're doing a 15-minute
meditation or something which is okay if
you're in a rush okay better than
nothing it's like a headstand in the
afternoon okay if you can't do your yoga
get used to doing headstands in weird
places okay like we do them in the
airport all the time we do them on the
plane in the kitchen you have to wait
until you're halfway over the it'll over
Hawaii then everyone's asleep you can do
your headstand in the kitchen but if you
can do ten minutes a you're gonna do it
if you can do fifteen minutes if you can
meditation for 15 minutes do it okay
then you don't have to do all this seven
steps but if you have like 45 minutes to
do a meditation you should do these
steps okay you should do it makes the
meditation really yummy okay the
meditation gets easy great things happen
you get happy because your meditations
so cool all right and if you don't do
this preparation it's like running a
race without excess it's like doing
ballet without stretching if you want to
kill yourself do ballet without
stretching so we're gonna talk about the
seven okay and I thought I will do an
EMT for $100 words not here right MT ten
nine eight
who said that I hate you you just give
the answer cuz she keeps the money yeah
how did dollars for the young man Wow
where'd that come from it's a way of
teaching lamb rim where you actually do
it together okay yum tea tea means to
teach young he got half of it I didn't
point that out still worth it yeah you
keep fifty given fifty fifty for you 54
no no you can have 100 the girlfriend
usually ends up with eighty or ninety
anyway there's a bad joke I could tell
about that but I'm gonna control myself
so here we go we're gonna do this seven
together okay as an EMT we'll do them
together now I'm gonna take you through
the preliminaries seven seven
ingredients tasty of the tasty cookie
called meditation and I'm gonna take you
one by one okay then I want you to
notice
you all did it many times okay when you
did something many times with me already
then then study how I teach it you see I
mean once you've already done the lions
dance a thousand times then see how I
teach it okay so I'm gonna take you
through the just a normal seven
preliminaries okay one of which is not
and I want you to I'm then I'm gonna
stop and I'm gonna ask you guys to tell
me what what did I do when I taught it
what are some things I did when I taught
it okay all right just try to notice the
technique of teaching the seven and what
do you notice okay usually just sit
there and do it right now you have to
sit there and do it and also think about
what I'm saying just refreshing what
what do I talk about what do I add what
do I don't add okay ready alright get
ready to meditate put down your notes
blow your nose in a strong way into the
microphone whenever you teach it's very
good if their student is sleeping write
down your notes okay
[Music]
before you start the first preliminary
you have you know get people to blow
their nose put your stuff away and for
God's sake turn off your cell phone this
demon of meditation they used to say
Johnny GaN be dark
say Johnny GaN be done da means sound
and it also means enemy in Tibetan so
they say the sounds in the room are the
enemy of meditation but now we have a
cellphone call beta cell phone is the
enemy of meditation ok so turn it off
you too Michael
I think so thank you alright then we'll
start I like what came to me by accident
this morning which is the reason you've
been suffering ichiraku through yoga for
all these years is for meditation those
yoga poses are called asana asana means
a sitting exercise how to prepare your
body for meditation so use your yoga you
know all this flexibility you have used
it used the inner strength use the
muscles the goal of yoga
why yoga was invented was to make it
easier to mmunity that's all it's not to
look good which is also a good thing or
show are for okay it's two minutes
its purpose is to meditate okay that's
why they're called asana ask me to us
really Anna Anna means maker right how
does sitter downer asana
where was the Buddha enlightened vaginal
simmer imagine asana the seed of the
diamond nowadays they call it but Gaia
but the old name is Vajrasana seed of
the diamond asana see so the word for
yoga poses is poses for city poses to
help you sit okay here we go then
please relax your face a little smile is
very helpful chronically with youichi
make sure your back is straight eyes can
be slightly open but don't look out of
them or they can be shut but don't get
sleepy I find it's helpful to close my
eyes but look up a little bit also in
yoga for dirty fingers are important
should be relaxed it's very good for the
prana if the first finger and the thumb
are touching or you can experiment you
can investigate part of each how it
feels to not quite touch the thumb and
the first finger try not to wrinkle your
forehead try to relax your forehead
there's a habit that we all have to
wrinkle your forehead when you meditate
when you concentrate so try not to then
eyelid should not be tense
and to warm up for the meditation we're
gonna do some breathing we're gonna take
ten slow breaths just to slow down the
mind and we're gonna count them from the
out-breath first and then the in-breath
one out-breath one in-breath that's one
try to make the out-breath as long as
you can and talk at the end of the out
breath then try to tighten your stomach
just a little bit so when you reach the
end of your out-breath then add a little
bit more out-breath and automatically
your stomach will clinch and that makes
your back stronger okay here we go ten
long pants long exhales don't worry
about the inhale through your nose if
you can if you if you have some kind of
cold or allergies then to your mouth is
okay
then I'd like you to think about one of
your teachers it doesn't have to be your
spiritual teacher your Lama could be any
of the teachers in your life we have had
many teachers were all very very lucky
that we had teachers guiding us through
life who have been through life before
and they teach us so many things our
first grade teachers are our mother and
our Father even if you don't have such a
good relationship with your mother or
your father still your mother
risked her life and she went through
incredible pain and trouble to give you
your life she almost traded her life for
your life and she taught you how to talk
how to walk how to eat how to poopoo how
to act around people your parents taught
you so many things you need in this life
without them we would be like animals
then we have school teachers very
dedicated people they don't get much
credit they don't get much money but
they help our society they help our
world they help our children we have
other kinds of teachers sports teachers
music teachers art teachers maybe you
have religious teachers in your school
or you or your church synagogue or your
temple your mosque you had people
teaching you about beautiful ideas
deeper ideas they were not perfect they
all have problems too but the world is
better if we have them that were our
world is more rich if we have pretty
and rabbis and Amundson people to help
us about spiritual things there are also
human they have their problems if we
didn't have them this world would be a
very poor place and maybe more violently
then you have your deep relationships
your wife your husband your children
your parents brothers and sisters uncles
aunts all of these people have taught
you your personal friends have taught
you and most importantly your enemies
have taught you in your life people who
gave you problems people who gave you
trouble they made you strong they made
you examine your life for mistakes so
the first thing the first step of the 7
is to invite one of those teachers to
come and stand in front of you they are
alive they are not a statue they are not
a photograph there are real person they
are sitting in front of you they are
warm you can smell the beautiful
fragrance from their body their eyes are
blinking their chest is rising up and
down they're alive they have come to
this room knee to knee to sit with us
and the first of the seven ingredients
is to prostrate to this person you know
if you come across god or an angel or a
buddha in your life in in the whole life
that you live if you ever meet a real
boon or angel Messenger of God or
whatever and you see who they are you
will you will automatically get down on
your hands and knees and you will throw
yourself on the ground this is a all
humans react the same way when they meet
holy beings without training without
being told they will get down under on
their body on their face they will they
will stretch their body on the ground in
front of this holy being this is if you
ever meet a Buddha or God or some angel
you will do that yourself no one has to
teach you no one has to tell you this is
the real prostration you can't stand up
in front of those things and you won't
even try in a meditation we don't want
to move our body our body is part so we
want to do a mental prostration we want
to bow down and it's very helpful to bow
down to something that you admire in
this teacher what is it about them that
you really love by the way I also wanted
to add it could be a historical teacher
like Mohammed or or Jesus or Buddha or
so couple or no gardener it could also
be your heart murmur and if you haven't
met your heart Lama yeah it could be the
person you are dreaming of to meet in
the future and bow down in your mind you
can't bend your mind down like you can
your body you can't put your hands on
the ground on your knees on the ground
with your mind the way you bow down with
your mind is to sync your mind things in
writings somebody into the beautiful
quality that you love about this teacher
sink your mind into the quality this is
mental bowing done and you're already
meditating before you start to meditate
sink your mind into some beautiful
[Music]
quality of this person so I'm going to
be quiet for a few minutes and please
think about good things of course every
person you can think of me also Buddha
tsongkhapa they looks like we all have
problems also we have our own faults we
make mistakes but when you do this first
of the seven ingredients don't think
about what's wrong with your teacher
think about what's right with your
teacher what's the most beautiful thing
about your teacher of course they make
mistakes of course there are things that
they do wrong but in this meditation
warm-up Suk Jong we want to make good
karma so we're going to think about the
most beautiful thing that we enjoy about
this teacher here we go it's going to be
about two minutes sink your mind Samadhi
into that beautiful quality try to feel
it
yeah then slowly come on open your eyes
take a stretch drink something
non-alcoholic okay I'm gonna I've been
teaching meditation for I don't know 35
years no 45 years what are some of the
things I do what are the some of the
things I did anything tell me let's go
teacher training yeah get people settled
down okay
don't try to meditate get it takes about
five minutes to get a crowd to settle
down just forget it
you can beg them not to move they will
move you can beg them not to do this
different thing they will do the Zippity
okay so let them get settled down okay
yeah what's something else by the way
that means you also have to have Kleenex
tissues available seriously if you're
gonna have a good meditation class you
know have some tissues around the room
okay next what you do it as you say it
do it as I say yeah demonstrate what
yeah would you take oh you know wake
them up just yeah raise your hand yeah
yeah good go through the body go for the
trouble spots okay what are the trouble
spots everyone almost everyone when they
focus this gets wrinkled and this goes
down okay your mom said it was gonna
stick your mom was right
start my mom told me that I didn't help
when I type I'm Oh hmm when I play music
oh okay so yeah there's trouble spots in
the human body shoulders are like this
fingers are clenched eyes are closed
okay what's the what else raise your
hand and yell it maybe like yeah an
excellent point
very important that's probably the most
important they have to bring a teacher
in the room okay now there's a lot to
say and it took me many years to
understand okay rule number one do not
make yourself the teacher okay do not
say I'm the mama focus on me okay if you
want people to criticize you or have a
bad meditation okay so you have in my
many years of experience okay
don't refer to yourself as the teacher
or the mama okay if they feel a
connection to you it will come okay you
don't have to talk about it okay some of
the people will and some of the people
will not and don't worry about it some
people will respect you as a teacher and
some people will criticize you in the
same room okay
and don't worry about it don't make
yourself the big teacher okay don't say
meditate on me and don't assume they
want you to be their teacher because
maybe they don't okay
maybe they don't have any other place to
learn meditation but they don't like you
now it happens okay so don't assume they
came here to be your disciple and
they're gonna throw money at you or
Donuts probably gonna throw bills at you
for the room and stuff so that's a very
important important point of you make
sure you give in a meditation class that
they have the freedom to bring a teacher
who's important to them okay don't push
a teacher on them
okay go through all the religions okay
in this room we have people who grew up
in Islam Catholicism Judaism Hinduism we
have everything Buddhist atheist so
respect them okay
then talk about different kinds of
teachers don't push the teacher on them
nobody likes it okay they want to
meditate on their sweet teacher so so
mention all the teachers you're
conveying I often mention a dog one guy
insisted to me his main teachers his dog
okay even dog so and to me it's
important to leave it open your future
heart teachers a lot of people say I
want to have a hard teacher I didn't
find them yet and when you're a
beginning teacher you're like it with me
smile you're so get used to it don't be
so proud no maybe you're not the root
Lama of anybody in the room that's okay
you can be your own morality don't be
all a lot of people get in trouble
teachers a CIT teachers many people got
in trouble could they want to be the
momma you know so just relax being
alarmist a lot of trouble actually so
relax some people will be attracted to
you and that's a beautiful thing and you
know
may I think about it we've been together
25 years hundred years and we have this
rich relationship and maybe some people
will so maybe some people that's okay
that's not your business okay you're in
meditation teacher okay
don't sell yourself okay some will some
will take you as a teacher
some women that's okay that's let them
find their one pair of jeans does not
fit the whole world trust me
I took a certain friend of mine and
started to the store to buy jeans no man
should ever go to the store when his
woman is buying jeans she tried 45 pairs
none of them fit okay now to think one
pair of jeans is gonna fit everybody in
this room it's impossible okay one llama
is not gonna fit everybody so don't sell
your stuff like that okay just say I'm
here to help you learn how to meditate
I'm sure you have other teachers so I
just want to give you my ideas my
suggestions okay good point up here a
very good point who else yeah Sagan yeah
I like to use humor I know it's not
everyone's style to be honest my llama
did never used to he used his fists and
his rosary now he only hit me like once
or twice but I probably deserved it but
um in general in the modern world people
enjoy if you're relaxed okay III I told
you a hundred times I'll tell you again
I sneaked into a meditation class that
my student was giving and I sat in the
back like a proud papa proud father you
know probably it's a team victory when
your kids are doing something right
you're like must be genetical then
I was thinking oh this is gonna be great
and then my student was very nervous and
like this and they were drinking coffee
here and then the two people in front of
me there were two ladies in front of me
I was hiding behind them and one of them
turn to the other one I said I don't
know what kind of meditation she's
teaching but I don't want to learn it
and I broke my heart you know come on
she's a good teacher and so you have to
be meditating to teach meditation okay
and just like in a yoga class so we
could tell today that it has a good
practice at home people can smell it if
you have a good meditation practice so
you don't okay don't try to get up and
fake a meditation class
it's hopeless okay anyone can tell even
your dog can tell you dogs like okay
other things I did anything yeah good
when you take them to the breathing by
the way I didn't jump straight into
inviting your teacher you you have to
get their posture straight then you have
to get their breath straight okay
there's things you have to do before you
start to seven like zero number zero
okay so yeah get their breathing
straight emphasize the out-breath if
someone asks you why you do the
out-breath first what's the answer
there's two answers editor
[Music]
in a normal life when you're born the
first breath is a breath in and when you
die the last breath is a breath out but
we would like to reverse that process or
change it so we would like to breed out
first and make that the first breath and
then breathe in so that we can bring the
winds into the okay it's an objection to
dying I know I'm not gonna end the
breath with the out-breath I'm sorry I'm
changing things I'm not dying the way I
used to die I'm not gonna take a last
breath and then it's done you know I'm
gonna and then I'm gonna stay alive so
the purpose of meditation is to become a
Buddha Buddhist don't die but don't take
their last breath okay so it's a
tradition to start the breath with the
out-breath and then always take an
in-breath okay there's another reason to
take a long out breath what's that to
take the title Prince like the air which
remains in the lungs
take it out yeah get the title air out
of your lungs so every time you breathe
out you never breathe out all the oxygen
you never breathe out all the air and
what happens during meditation is it
builds up okay so if you don't it's a
very easy very effective way to keep a
good state of mind in meditation it's
long exhales okay after the natural end
of the exhale exhale a little bit more
okay
just like okay what
okay little more then take the puzzle
okay and then this air doesn't build up
in the body if it builds up you get a
nervous condition and if you ever try to
do a long retreat longer than two days
you will experience what we call lung
which is in Tibetan which is a buildup
of this prana and your hands start
shaking and you start getting headaches
and your breath speeds up your
heartbeats pizza you get pains all over
your body and it can last for years okay
so it's a very simple easy way to teach
people breathe out and then breathe a
little bit more it's also useful in a
lot of yoga poses like twists so breathe
out and then breathe a little more in
interest but if you if you forget
everything else we talked about tonight
that's the most important thing okay if
you don't if you forget to teach that
you could ruin their meditation practice
okay it's like making people do poses
that hurt them okay which many yoga
teachers do by accident so it's very
important that you teach them to exhale
twice in innocence okay anything else I
did yes mister Stanley first of all you
give explanation of each ingredient and
then you actually leave time for us to
meditate on it you don't just talk and
move on you stay and pause and let us
meditate on it good I went to a
meditation class by one of my students
they talked the whole time
they didn't meditate that's like a maze
that's like why I have to see this
that's a DCI teacher has something why I
have to say this this guy talked the
whole time he didn't manage me don't
don't do that okay people came to
meditate all right if you want to upset
them talk the whole time all right by
the way if you team teach which I've
also seen one teacher is more pushy and
does all the talking and the other
teachers like and they never get to say
anything okay it's sweet to teach us a
team two people teaching meditation is
very sweet but equal rights okay
anything else yes ma'am our teacher is
not perfect yeah it's it's important to
say look your teacher is not perfect
this morning how did I put it everybody
has mixed Karma we all have mixed karma
cannot lend a comma shuklar krishna yo
guinness Trivedi metallation
fourth chapter yoga Sutra we all have
white and black crumble okay so
naturally you're gonna see your teacher
make mistakes so where do I often go
with that by the way we should thank you
because she did all the yoga poses for
the DCI photo layout for the manual and
thank you for them
[Music]
we are using it in many countries you're
famous
just nobody knows you that's beautiful
yoga practice thank you yeah yeah where
do I go sometimes come on if you want to
say something naughty what's the famous
joke yeah
don't smell a fart twice duty younger
man don't say duty if the person next to
you make a fire don't go just turn your
nose if you're smart of course you did
you have some fun but don't smell it
again and again try to think about the
good quality they have a few everybody
even Trump has some good cause he can't
be President forever it's a hill they go
that's a good quality I I try when you
will ask us to sit like teachers
especially parents you mentioned many
details like you know how your parents
teach you to talk and how do you know
without them you know how to poopoo you
know even taste and I say this part it
brings a lot of a strong appreciation
it's very important for me there's a
reason for also I'll tell you something
motivation I have when I talk about
parents okay if your parents
are happy about your Buddhism your
practice will succeed if your parents
are not happy about your Buddhism you
will have some difficulty it's not
impossible but you will have difficulty
okay so I was driving with a guy his
name is I forget his name he's called I
forget anyway
maroon he's from Lebanon he lives in
Ireland okay and we were driving in his
car he was driving around and his
daughter was with us little daughter
she's like six seven years old and she
doesn't like me because if daddy
meditates in the morning and doesn't pay
attention to her so she figured out it's
my fault and she's like Danny why do you
do this meditation every money you know
and my room is very cool and he said
well honey daddy has to do his
meditation so why why you don't want to
play with me and he said well daddy you
know daddy used to get angry all the
time and then daddy had to meditate and
then he said a beautiful thing he asked
her did you see daddy get angry
since he's meditating every day and
she's like that's right that's true
daddy didn't get angry you'll keep that
humanity okay so you need your family
support okay so if you're a teacher
whenever you meet the parents tell them
how cool they are thank you for having
your baby they're very they're my best
students you must be the best parent in
the world right okay you have to as a
teacher of Buddhism or anything else you
have to get the parents on your side
and you have to get the kids on your
side okay so uh and it's not untrue it's
totally true everything they did for you
okay now in America there's a problem
that many people have trouble with their
parents we don't have a culture in
America of respecting your parents we
don't have it okay we disrespect our
parents a lot and we don't thank them
and until we have kids of our own right
I saw Nick I was there two days ago the
baby came out me and Veronica were there
and the parents were both parents sets
of parents were there and then Nick was
like thanks mom Thanks oh my god oh my
god you did this twice everybody figures
it out when they have their own baby
what your mother went through but in
America it's very common that people
won't respect their parents people won't
thank them so I and I think in the world
one of the basic causes of peace is
respect between the generations you see
if if the children respect the parents
if the parents respect the grandparents
then society is healthy and people get
along and and the world works better if
everyone respects their parents okay so
you can make a teaching during the
meditation preliminaries to cause this
kind of harmony in the world if the
parents respect their parents if the
children respect their parents then
there's much greater harmony in society
okay so use the meditation preparation
as an excuse to give a sermon about
parents okay and in American audience
you have to say something
I know maybe you don't like your mother
maybe she wasn't the one you thought was
perfect mom but look she almost died to
give you birth hey maybe she helped you
a little you know some in America where
we don't respect our parents I think
it's good to talk about okay anything
else if you're given to me quick you can
have a pee-pee break yes
you give options when you are especially
when you say you have to close our eyes
you keep options yeah good that's a very
cool observation give people options
some people don't feel comfortable when
they close their eyes and the scriptures
say you can close your eyes are not
close your eyes what's an important
other option to give people your hands
there's like four positions right one
two three four okay five okay left hand
down right hand you could go like this
to keep it up it's distracting you can
just put it down okay
took me like five years to figure it out
by the way if you're in a hot room this
works better because there's
air-conditioning here I'm not kidding I
did retreat in 120 degrees 45 Celsius I
was in the yoga just dripping and it
would snow the first three weeks it's
known we didn't have any heat so I
learned when you're cold when it snows
this is better because your body builds
up heat here okay and when it's hot then
move the fingers to the knees and it
creates air here and you you you you
don't get so hot okay
so give people options here especially
about what city how they sit okay how
they sit don't force people to cross
their legs okay
what's the joke I like to give indicia
why didn't sit in a chair and anyone's
like now technically if you can sit in a
half Lotus or full Lotus it will help
your meditation and I don't say you
never heard me say that right on a DC I
turn you never heard me say that because
I don't want everyone breaking their
legs okay but between us Buddhist people
teachers if you can do a lotus half
Lotus or practice it's just practice and
it's and it's yoga and you can keep it
for an hour to three hours okay and if
you practice okay if you don't practice
and you try to do it you will
permanently damage your knees their
knees are very easy to permanently
damaged okay so don't push it do it you
know do it for a minute then do it for
five minutes then do it for ten minutes
then you can sit like that for two three
hours it's okay okay I have another just
among Buddhists okay if your legs fall
asleep let them fall asleep okay don't
move okay let them fight it hurts for
five minutes then you can't feel
anything it's like dentist it's kind of
nice if they fall asleep be careful how
you stand up my friend broke his ankle
when he stood up too fast
but nothing faster don't freak out it's
okay they just passed it then you can
meditate better okay it hurts for five
minutes or maybe ten and then let them
fall okay anything else about that one
let me think if I have anything to add
[Music]
something I should say which I haven't
done tonight is keep it moving okay
don't spend 20 minutes on the teacher
you will you can't meditate for two
hours you don't have time you know
family you have job you have other
things to do and you cannot focus that
long so keep it moving keep it on a pace
okay if you want to know I use my breath
as a clock I do 10 breaths on each one
if I have a lot of time I do 20 if I
have a lot of a lot of time I do if I'm
at Diamond Mountain I do 30 breaths okay
but normal for me is 10 breaths on each
step and keep it moving
so my breath is my clock okay keeping
keeping don't get stuck don't get bogged
down my teacher is not so happy today
my teacher must be eating a lot of
Trudeau's
keep it you have to keep it moving okay
what else yeah teach the real meaning of
prostration teach the balloon by the way
when you read the reading which I'm sure
you're doing every day I translated the
greatest instructions for these seven
from two sources one is jetsam copper
London symbol the great book on the
steps of the path the most famous
Buddhist book into the 1,000 pages and I
put it in your reading if you don't read
the reading I get irritated because it's
so much work okay
is similar again I spent all day today
on the homework for tomorrow and I
didn't finish ok I got Tim giving means
vibes I'm finished tonight I promise but
anyway the reading is great now in the
reading what kind of prostration do they
do for $50 I mean by the way welcome on
a and husband they just got married to
this remark it thank you for coming I
know you have I know this is the
strangest honeymoon we love you and
we're very happy you're here you both
got a good fish I like I think you both
did a good job
Oh what kind of prostration $50 yes
in the reading what's the prostration
comes from Samantha butter
[Music]
okay cancel the button you you make
prostrations to every Buddha in the
universe at the same time okay it's not
your favorite high school teacher okay
in in if you want to do the advanced
version of this prostration you at the
same time you imagine your body splits
into billions and billions of bodies and
each body bounced down to a Buddha in
the universe
okay it's very fun you should check out
the Stars tonight hmm
the two biggest planets Jupiter and
Saturn are on each side of the moon it's
very powerful night if you have time
check it out there's two bright stars
like sitting next to the moon it's very
unusual as Jupiter and Saturn the two
most powerful biggest gravity that's why
you're so smart tonight okay anyway okay
I think that's all so that that
technically if you read the reading the
prostration can be done to every Buddha
in the universe at the same time and
there's a there's a very famous Sutra
that says all the buddhas in the
universe can fit on the tip of a needle
all the buddhas in the universe can fit
on the tip of a needle okay so not so
difficult to cover all of them just get
a little get something and say everybody
get here
okay so if you want to do the big one
I'm teaching you that the practical ones
that I learned from my teacher okay and
my teacher was very very extraordinary
and I learned a lot of things from him
that you don't find in the books you
know but he knew all the books also okay
so that's useful all right
the book says you should have a pee-pee
break okay then we'll then we'll
continue what's the next of the seven
Chuck's are well chosen offering okay
we're gonna talk about often we're gonna
do it together and you're gonna tell me
some tricks that I learned okay take a
break all right we're gonna continue so
please get ready to meditate turn off
your phone blow your nose a lot of
people failed in meditation because
they're too serious many many people
they got very nervous and what do you
call tight I have to do I tried to
meditate for I don't know almost 50
years I think John Bailey did more than
that
and you gotta relax okay you gotta have
fun okay if you don't have fun you you
will never be a good meditator okay
don't be so serious okay life is very
short have fun and you will meditate
better okay and you will have all this
Buddhist don't like grumpy people
nervous they don't come they also want
to have fun okay all right you guys
ready
is there anything you can make noise
with one minute from now yeah and it
crumpled something walk in and out of
the door all right here we go second of
the seven how we're gonna finish seven
tonight I have no idea okay let's start
with your breath long exhales let the
inhale take care of itself
we'll take ten long breath
you
the second of the seven ingredients is
to make an offering to the teacher who's
sitting in front of us
traditional offerings like Samantabhadra
special prayer is to imagine the whole
sky covered with roses or flowers lotus
flowers any kind of flowers so the whole
sky is covered with flowers this is a
very famous offering in Tantra we use
argan body and we used these offerings
you can wash your llamas feet with a
nice pure water you can offer them a
glass of crystal-clear water
second one you can offer them flowers
you can offer them incense you can offer
them a butter lamp or candle you can
imagine putting perfume on their body
you can imagine cooking them a nice meal
or giving them something yummy to eat or
you can imagine music these are
traditional offerings to the lama and
then every book says the same thing but
the greatest offering and we had it in
the lama chiba last night is to offer
the good things you've done this week so
of course we made mistakes we are not
great people but we're trying we're all
trying our best and we did some sweet
things this week we did we did do some
nice things for other people
so in the highest form of offering to
your teacher is to share with them
something sweet that you did this week
maybe you visited a sick person or maybe
you taught yoga class meditation class
maybe you traveled around the world to
get some beautiful teachings about the
gardener so whatever those of you who
have families or parents you're serving
all day all night for many years you can
offer those karmic seeds to your teacher
and this is the greatest offering you
can make because if the person is your
teacher they want to see you happy to be
a teacher the reason we teach piano or
we teach a foreign language or we teach
meditation is we want to help the other
person we want to see them succeed so if
they tell us all the good comments
they're doing then that's the best thing
they can do to help themselves so of
course it makes mommy and daddy and Lama
happy when people are doing sweet things
for other people then they feel proud
and they feel happy because you are
going to become a Buddha quickly so of
course you can make other offerings when
we go to Temple we offer incense when we
go to church we offer money we can do
many offerings but the highest offering
is to serve other people and to love
other people this is the offering that
pleases
you teacher the most the word for
offering my teacher often said the word
in Sanskrit for offering his puja and
the road of the Sanskrit means to make
your teacher happy
it is the puja is offering the highest
prayer you can do the highest ceremony
you can do is to offer your teacher
sweet things you've done for other
people especially this week okay open
your eyes take a stretch what are some
tricks about teaching the second one if
you've been you know been trying to
teach meditation for almost 50 years
what what did I mention what do I think
is important yeah it's the most
important point when you teach people
about offering get them out of the idea
that physical offerings are the most
important okay because we grow up in a
Buddhist family or a Muslim family or
Christian family we're supposed to make
zakat
zakat we're supposed to make donation in
the Christian we are supposed to make
weekly donation you know we're supposed
to burn incense for the ancestors and
and you those are good things those are
sweet things those are important things
we should do them but it's not the
highest form of offerings okay the
highest form of offering is to offer
your good deeds to your teacher okay by
the way one thing I forgot to mention
about the prostration right mental
prostration that's coffee meditation
okay there's two kinds of coffee
meditation one is about your own good
deeds and one is about other people's
good deeds okay so when you bow down to
your teachers good qualities you are
doing a coffee meditation on your
teacher and kind of in number two you're
kind of doing a confer meditation on
yourself your brag there's always kids
you see kids in every country it doesn't
matter what country that they draw some
very ugly thing at school and the
teacher says go home give it to mom you
know and they bring it home and if the
mom is chill she she said oh that's so
beautiful let's put it on the wall you
know and then the kid is like oh mom
like my offering so you teachers
probably thinking oh this is is that the
best good thing you could do but but
still they say oh amazing
oh you made a tea for somebody Wow
you're special
3,000 people died in Africa the same day
and you ignored them that's okay okay
but anyway yeah there's still happy with
the small things that the kids do
they're happy all right anything else we
mentioned yeah then you slowly go up
which makes it very clear that there is
a hierarchy and that the mental one is
the most important one and you don't
just jump into the mental one
immediately yeah I like that I used to
just jump into the offering your good
deeds but sometimes Buddha likes a
flower you know
or sometimes buddha like some music by
the way when you offer music if you want
to have an interesting conversation with
somebody plate you know play rock and
roll in taiwan right where's the Olly
play rock and play old 60s rock and roll
in Taiwan who people don't never heard
it before and it sounds like a bus with
the brakes broken crashing into a taxi
but I had many interesting conversations
in my life people said gala that's not
religious music and I'm like what's
religious movie show me religious music
because I grew up in the church right
Princeton University Chapel is the
biggest in the United States maybe and
the music is quiet you know did I rented
a Buddhist temple
[Music]
that's not religious music my lamas
religious music it sounds terrible if
you wanna have a fight with someone try
to decide what's religious meaning
what's not I decided rappers not
religious music then Veronica's fighting
with me every day even rappers I know
impossible any music you love is
religious okay any music you offer is
religious music come on you know every
country has different customs okay
China eat I don't know I said I have so
many sweet students from Vietnam I
should learn to eat my Vietnamese food
so I went to Vietnamese restaurant I
said give me the heart spicy hot pot oh
my god
[Music]
[Laughter]
then I take my vietnamese friend let's I
took him standing to boots pizza the
best pizza in America
what's the two boots one is Louisiana
which is spicy food and one is the boot
of Italy the shape of Italy so it's the
best when I did my sri retreat we had a
person fly a pizza from New York to
Phoenix on the lap from the two bits and
I'm like Stanley I'm gonna take you to
the best pizza in the universe you know
you say oh thank you he's like do you
like it
mmm what's the best way to insult
somebody about your food it's
interesting very interesting
it's a this a Chinese word it means it
sucks cuz you know it's lousy I don't
like it so come on you know offer what's
sweet to you it's okay okay what music
you like it's okay Buddha's happy trust
me people ask me games on when we do the
prayer should we ring the bell with the
left hand
or she would mean the building right
here hi which one this Buddha like oh
it's okay good as happy your ringing
Bell it's okay okay don't don't don't
get all pick out about offering okay of
course offer the things that you enjoy
okay
my mama has to get used to popcorn
chocolate and milk shake those are the
highest offering okay I understand
don't get cultural don't get culture
Buddhists have more they don't have a
country they have all countries they
like hotpot Vietnamese and they like
pizza everything's okay but
offer them something all right here we
go ready for the next one
charts are welshing shushing there's a
special verse you can about the seven
maybe I'll teach it to you sometime here
we go
when llamas forget the seven they do the
first Chaucer or some tuition shopping
shopping shopping
here we go shoppin ready meditate
ten breaths just to get into the
meditation don't forget even on a short
meditation long exhales
so the third of the seven is confession
which in Tibetan is called chakra Shabba
means to split a piece of wood with an
axe and so it means you open your heart
you open your chest and you open your
heart and you let the Lama look inside
you're not the teacher look inside and
you don't hide anything so the main
thing about our bad deeds the things
mistakes we make we work very hard to
hide them I also do it we work very hard
to cover our mistakes to hide our
mistakes we don't want people to know
about our weaknesses or our bad habits
we want to keep them secret and that
makes the karma very serious so if we
can even just mentally in our meditation
open your heart and tell ask your Lama
please look into my heart and I've have
made these mistakes and I admit them the
thing that strange about this third
ingredient is you cannot hide anything
from your lama it's not possible if
there are Buddha they can see everything
you're doing all the time okay so we
have this strange bad habit we try to
hide our mistakes especially from our
teacher we try to hide them we don't
want them to see we don't want them to
think we're a bad person so we hide our
mistakes in this third of the seven
ingredients chime very hard to you know
talk to your Lama
I know you already know everything I'm
thinking I know you can see everything
I'm doing already and I'm not gonna hide
anything from you
when I'm walking around in my normal
life maybe I'm not strong enough and I
will hide things but between us in the
privacy of our my meditation with you I
want you to know everything I'm thinking
everything I'm doing and I want you to
help me purify my mistakes I I'm not so
strong that I can never make this
mistake again probably I'll make it
today again but I want you to know I'm
trying and I want you to know I make
mistakes and I want you to know my
mistakes and please help me to clean
them and please help me to be stronger
next time then you spend a few minutes
and think about the biggest mistakes you
made this week and it's an honesty
exercise the name of the game is honesty
how honest can you be to yourself and be
honest to your teacher you can't hide
anything from them anyway
when you try it's kind of stupid okay so
just admit everything I had I lived for
25-30 years with my teacher I made
mistakes as a monk and I made a promise
to myself that I would tell him whenever
I made that mistake and I would go to
his room the first time was very
embarrassing I told him you know I broke
this phone I couldn't help it and he he
gave me some you know practices to fix
it I made a promise to myself that I
would tell my mama every time I broke
her about it got to be very funny
sometimes later when I knock on the door
he will say are you gonna tell me about
broken vows I said yeah he said go away
I already heard you know but it's a very
very good exercise to be totally honest
with somebody in your life maybe you're
the teacher you're picturing
it's a good habit just to do everything
honestly in business in teaching
everything is much easier if you're a
hundred percent honest all the time so
let's spend a few minutes and think
about some mistakes we made this week we
don't have time to think about all of
them but think about some of the big
ones the bad habits okay here we go we
have to get rid of these scenes because
the purpose of these seven is to
meditate we want to have a good
meditation if we don't at least tell our
Lama about those seeds we will not have
a good meditation we will be distracted
you
and by the end of this step you should
believe that your heart is pure that
those seeds are gone
okay open your eyes honesty kills bad
sees okay honesty kills bad okay what
are some things you can do what are some
things I did yeah
with with with sharpen with confession
the name of the game is honesty okay
just be honest with one person in your
life totally honest it's hard to be
honest with everybody because your
friends will move away if you tell them
everything but there should be one
person in your life that you're
completely honest with okay in your
business dealings in your day-to-day
life I mean I'm telling you from 66
right from 66 it's just easier to be a
hundred percent honest everything you do
it's just easier okay
taxes business personal relationships
everything goes better with honesty it's
like salt not like Vietnamese chilies
okay everything goes better with assault
it's okay just be be honest whatever you
do it's just easier okay I'm telling you
I tried the other it doesn't work just
be honest to be honest about who you are
and be honest about your bad habits your
mistakes okay the more honest you are
the better you can fight okay anything
else yes IG the Buddha Reno or the
battery step we have done you know
oh I know you know ready so I can touch
it review everything she sees you know
account engagement yeah I think it's
it's a good thing to say look they
already know you can't hide anything so
don't bother trying to hide that's
another important thing I think you also
mentioned that like like everybody deep
mistakes you know like then somebody
feels that chill I'm not so bad so I
think that pie is very nice it's all I
think it's important from a Buddhist
teacher a CI teacher to admit that you
also make mistakes okay I mean it's just
important you can try to be a perfect
teacher you will go crazy nobody
believes you in any way you know I think
it's more healthy for everybody and
that's why I like to tell the story
about going to tell my teacher when I
broke about you know then the audience
gets more comfortable even guys have
these problems you know and he also went
to his teacher his teacher also told him
to get the hell out of the room so I
think when you're teaching confession
it's very powerful if you can just
mention your own mistakes also and it
just makes the whole room more calm you
know we all make mistakes okay it's
better if you say it it makes everyone
feel better if you didn't make mistakes
you would already be in a Buddha
paradise okay if you're here it's
because you made mistakes so don't try
to lie about it if you're here you may
miss them we all know you wouldn't be
here if you did this is where they put
the dumb students I think encourage
people to be honest by the way we do so
joke right the monks and nuns one of the
main things that monks and nuns do is so
jaam twice a month we're supposed to get
together and we're supposed to tell each
other the mistakes we made that's the
main monks practice that's the main nuns
practice in nowadays in the big finish
you know I'm like where are we gonna
tell each other about the bad things
oh we finished it just became people
just and it they lost the custom in the
monastery I'm sorry to say 3,000 monks
choose each other but they were leather
but never geeky not too much I did let
me get relaxed so then everybody's like
can we go
and then ants in our own organization
they are keeping a very good practice of
so Joan they call each other on skype
and they actually talk about their
mistakes okay so if you can find at
least one friend in your life that you
can be honest with them you know you can
go to the coffee shop do some shot but
you know there's over shock but also
right someone want to tell you for two
hours of dr. all the bad deeds so don't
do that
okay that's overshot but we don't want
to hear about you know all your bad days
just tell us a few some people just want
to talk about themselves over and over
okay don't do that all right that's car
you ready for the next one Chuck saw us
into she shopped with them Jason you
know Jairam rejoice coffee meditation
time here we go by the way we have about
another half hour okay
I'll try to finish on money they knew
each other or money they made
ten breaths
you
so when I was living with my llama he
got invited at the the pub in Rome the
head of the Catholic Church Milly I
don't know hundred million Catholics he
decided every church should invite other
religions people to give a talk
so my llama was invited to the local
Catholic Church to give a talk and we
actually went to the Cathedral big big
big Christian temple and I remember we I
was his driver so we drove I drove with
him and then the priest met him and he
was a very nice priest and he said do
you want to see the Cathedral my momma
said yeah sure and we walked down the
middle of the Cathedral and my momma was
like take notes Mike take notes there's
some good stuff here and he said what's
all those special windows with all the
pictures and all the colors and the
priest said oh these are stained-glass
window what's all those people in the
window oh those are stories of saints
and people can look at them and remember
the Saints and my teacher its timing
okay Mike let's do this let's take class
inner Buddhist temple okay write that
down we're not supposed to show the
priest to be running it done then that
we went halfway down the Cathedral being
Cathedral and on the right hand side
there was a small room and there were
two doors and a priest went into one
door and the woman went in the other
door in my momma said to the
Oh father you know what's going on over
there why the priest Conan and the
woman's going in the piece of don't
worry don't worry
this is confession you know the priest
will listen to the woman in a through a
window and the woman will tell her
mistakes and the priest will purify help
her purified with mistakes did my llama
says well what how they purify the
sticks he said oh they give them some
prayers to do Hail Mary Paris you do 100
prayers or 200-person my Lama said oh
that's a great idea we do that also we
did exactly the same thing that's a
great great thing then he turned around
to the left side of the church and he
has two priests where's the other one
and the priest said what do you mean he
said where's the other room and it
Pistor what do you mean the other room
in my Lama said where's the room where
you the priest goes in and the woman
goes in and then the woman tells the
priest all the good things she did last
week and the priest is like wow that's a
good idea maybe we'll start that he did
he started making notes you know make a
rejoice enough instead of a confessional
and it's a special little room where you
go in and you tell the priest all the
good things you did last week and my
Lama when we got home he said you know
it's it's amazing if this religion is
2,000 years old
and they don't have a rejoice in all you
know didn't they figure it out that you
have to have both you have to tell your
teacher all the mistakes you made but it
is equally important hundred percent
equally important that you tell your
teacher all the good things you did last
week you must reinforce
good habits you have and you must
confess the bad habits you so this is
called Jisoo Iran it means to be happy
about the good things you did last week
you can also be happy about the good
things other people are doing because
you have the Karma to see them so please
give an equal time and we're gonna do it
right now give it 10 or 20 breaths and
please think about all the cool stuff
you've been doing in the last week
everyone here I know most of you pretty
well you are doing amazing things so
come on let's have some heavy coffee
meditation here here we go
[Music]
you
then slowly open your eyes take a
stretch okay what are some important
things to talk about when you're doing
this step what's step number four yeah
what's important thing to talk about if
you're teaching yeah I you know alex is
right you can talk about it for two
hours you can tell people give equal
time to coffee meditation and they
cannot do it all over the world okay you
can tell me but don't kill they will
stop killing you can tell them don't eat
me they will stop eating me
you can tell them to be happy about
their good days they can't do it all
over the world it's amazing I don't know
what it is it's the same in every
country you know people feel shy or
embarrassed or they feel like it's pride
okay you have to one of your biggest
jobs as an ACI teacher is not to teach
people what they're not doing is to
teach people about the good things they
are doing already and they just can't
hear it so say it again and again and
again and again okay you are already
doing amazing things okay
you are already a special person and you
can take it to the rim you know you you
people in this room are one in in 30
million or three million you're one in
three million people in this country
that for every person here there's two
million 999,999 people who didn't make
it into this room okay maybe you're
special
okay like you got a I don't know what it
is everywhere I go in the world people
have trouble with this with this one
it's strange right you think they will
have trouble to admit their mistakes no
they have trouble to admit their good
deeds you know I don't know what it is
but you're gonna have to it's your
life's work if you're gonna be a ACI
teacher if you're artist you're supposed
to paint the greatest painting if you're
a musician you're supposed to make the
greatest song if you're an ACI teacher
you are trying to make people enjoy
their good deeds it's almost impossible
it's the hardest job you have it's the
fun job but it's a hard job people have
trouble enjoying how good they are okay
so it's it's a big big job for you okay
what's the most difficult job you're
gonna have as an ESL teacher it's not to
get people to keep the ten good beads or
get them to meditate or get them to do
yoga those are easier than getting
people to enjoy their own good days okay
it's very difficult okay and it's the
and it's the sweetest thing you can give
them okay
so work hard on it okay don't don't be
lazy okay don't be lazy if you're gonna
be an architect build a great building
if you're gonna be a musician write the
greatest symphony if you're gonna be an
ACI teacher create people who enjoy
doing good deeds and and who enjoy their
own good deeds okay and it's very
difficult okay but that's your job okay
you are not there to teach them eighteen
more kinds of emptiness like gosh you
mark up those okay if you can create
students who have fun and enjoy their
own goodness your success your teaching
will be a success and they will see
emptiness directly okay all right got it
big connection big connection
that's all I and I'm speaking from
experience we teach 35,000 people here
in DC I we try to teach them the four
steps we try to get them to do coffee
meditation it's extremely difficult okay
so if you have new ideas and you'd like
to share them I'm open to that too you
know if you have some new ideas how to
get people to enjoy their own good deeds
we need help there seems to be an
international problem I'm not talking
about pride everyone has plenty of pride
okay you don't have to teach pride
everyone has it already okay
I argue the smartest student in this
school yeah did you do any good deeds
last week I don't know I don't do good
deeds
yeah shut up all right let's go again we
still have ten minutes okay ready here
we go next one maybe we can finish this
seven okay here we go five breaths
d-bags
in this preliminary we asked for
teaching please give me more teaching so
you can talk to your teacher then they I
imagine the teachers always say well
what kind of teaching do you want and
then you're gonna say oh I want more
classes can I have more classes can we
do Micajah then we can do shanti devi
and then can we do it so kappa can we
have more classes and I imagine the
teachers say okay I'm happy to give you
more classes that's okay and then you
you can say I also want more private
teaching so we called um Rock I want
walk intoxication Michael I want to come
to his kitchen of his retreat cabin I
want to talk about my life I want
personal teachings preferably Tantra you
know I want guest lot to share secret
teachings with me in private I want that
okay and then the Lama says okay we can
do that we can do that and then the Lama
said do you want the highest teachings
do you want the highest teachings then
you say of course I want the highest
teaching well why why didn't you ask for
them well what's the highest teaching
highest teaching is when people
criticize you or you make enemies and
they try to hurt you these are the
highest teachers in your life okay so in
this ingredient of the seven you're
asking for teaching three kinds of
teaching number one oh I want special
classes okay I want classes okay you can
have number two what I want private
teaching I want the special teachings
you know okay you can have that number
three I want hard teachings I'm strong
I'm a strong meditator I'm a strong yogi
I want hard teachings hard teachings
means
I want people to be angry at me I want
people to hurt me
I want people to cheat me I want people
to use me and take advantage of me and I
want to be a peacock like from Satan's
text I want to eat the poison of the
world and become more beautiful okay so
I pray for those three kinds of
teachings I want all of them not just
classroom teaching and not just private
teaching I want the hard teachings that
angry people give me or people who cheat
me or my wife or my husband when they're
yelling at me I want those teachings
because I want to be strong I want to
serve the world and only strong people
can serve the world then that's all
requests teaching of those three kinds
and but important thing to tell people
when those teachings come to you don't
complain okay when when people get angry
at you or people cheat you or your wife
or your husband is unhappy with you then
take it as a teaching and use it to
improve yourself spiritually and don't
whine about it because this morning in
your meditation warm-up you specifically
asked for it so when it comes I don't
want to hear you complaining about it
okay open your eyes
got it okay the best teachings you ever
got were from your ex-wife ex-husband
ex-boyfriends okay they show you pain
they show you anger they test you in
weightlifting I used to be a
weightlifter believed in
both racing boats for Princeton and they
kill you they really kill you and they
if you don't pick up the heavy weight
that coach says get out get out of here
I want to see more than last week so
that's the angry people you know you
have to keep improving the only person
can improve you is irritating people and
bad drivers and stupid people who have
screaming babies behind you on the
flight back to China so don't forget you
asked for it during the meditation they
are just delivering what you asked for
don't get mad at the postman got it okay
okay one more ready one more two more
okay don't worry I'm gonna put you to
bed soon dad's gonna put you to bed
ready two more here we go three breaths
next time ask those teachers to stay in
your life please stay in my mind okay
don't leave me okay I know I'm a bad
student I know I never do what you tell
me to do I know you keep repeating the
same teachers over and over and over I
know my head is made of cement but
please please please don't leave me here
alone okay don't leave me okay please
stay with me
I'm trying I'm not very good I'm not the
best student in the world but I do come
to Diamond Mountain I do try to meditate
I tried to understand all these things
I'm trying from my side I'm trying and
from your side I know you have the power
to stay alive in my world
and I ask you from my face I ask you
please stay in my life and don't leave
me
okay open your eyes I think that one
doesn't need much explanation llama
karma is very expensive you burn a lot
of good karma by coming to bed mom we
had a Chinese guest a teacher came here
and we we offered him many beautiful
things and he refused them and we're
like what's the problem he said I don't
want to use that for my good karma my
friend in New York microwave right it's
impossible to find a parking spot in his
place
then when he finds one he drives past it
I'm like what are you doing
he said geez I don't want to use it but
my good karma
okay
it's very expensive to have a teacher in
your life the car you are burning a lot
of karma okay very very expensive to
have a real teacher in your life okay so
keep thanking them what's the best way
do your practice helped other people
okay if you're serious about keeping
your number help other people that's the
payment that they want okay that's the
only payment they want they don't need
your money they don't need your
chocolate bars something happen to my
flower stuff they don't need it did I
need anything you have
they just need your good deeds okay
that's all they really want okay so if
they keeps if you keep trying
they will stay if you keep trying
devasting all right that's the payment
okay one more we have two minutes here
we go so getting a question or from I
know
it takes me two minutes to stop talking
I'm like a big truck you know hard to
stop it here we go last meditation one
breath tonight I worked hard I flew to
this country from another country I took
all the time off my family's mad at me
my boss at work is mad at me everyone's
mad at me
I came here for some peace you know I
drove out in the middle of this desert
you know I'm trying I spend a lot of
money I spend a lot of time you know I'm
happy about my progress it's not perfect
I'm not a great person but dang it I'm
I'm really trying hard and I'm doing the
best I can and I appreciate the chance
to help people I appreciate the chance
to learn these things I I'm doing I'm
not a good person I'm not a perfect
person but I'm really trying hard to be
to learn how to be a good person and I
celebrate my success I've made some
success I'm still here I didn't give up
and I would be stubborn I'll be a donkey
Dharma donkey I will keep trying as hard
as I can and I'm happy that I'm trying
so hard and I offer that to my teacher
and I offer the good karma of all my
Dharma practice all my meditations all
my painful yoga classes
all my practice all my service I offer
it all the good karma to other people
I end it to other people may it help
your life then I I like to tell people
to make three deep exhales okay imagine
golden light going out to the whole
world this seventh of the seventh
preliminary which is the dedication of
your good deeds it actually goes after
the meditation so it's a preliminary for
meditation but it goes after the
meditation it's the last thing you do
before you stand up and go to work or
something okay all right open your eyes
and those are the seven yay okay I want
to see if I covered all the homework I
still have one meaning yeah all of this
six preliminaries and seven ingredients
for a meditation session have come from
some couple thirteen fifty seven to
fourteen nineteen if you have Buddhist
friends in this group and you want to
get into their bank account
the password is always one three five
seven just so coppice birthday but you
have to split the money with me okay the
original Sanskrit book where these seven
ingredients come from is called the
prayer of Samantha Bhadra the prayer of
Samantha Roger
it's a sutra it's an ancient sutra these
seven ingredients the six permanent they
come from this text and I translated
in your meeting okay so you have mmm
then you're supposed to give the seven
ingredients there's a question of where
do the seven ingredients fit in the six
preliminaries the answer is sucked down
when you do your confession classically
you should especially confess mistakes
you made against your vows okay like you
made a promise you wouldn't break this
thing and then you broke it okay so
three kinds of vows first one is called
freedom does okay those are like monks
vows laymen bounce okay
second vows Bodhisattva vows and we will
have body something else right Jimmy at
the fire offering so people were asking
me are we gonna get Bodhisattva bells if
you took the course okay with some other
deals I have made okay yeah you're
welcome to take them then can I get them
to you I will be one of the people
giving them to you okay so don't worry
about it I don't get them very often
okay like once every three four years
okay all right then the third kind of
vows is secret vows and you can learn
about this somebody sent me a text
yesterday email Kayla there's a secret
book in Buddhism about yoga here's the
translation that's been published and
I'm like that's sick anyway
secret boss don't ask me what they are
finish your 18 courses okay next
question
what's the difference between a prayer
and a dedication okay
it's different words and Sanskrit
different words in Tibetan okay my mom
and more say mom
more they are both similar you say I
hope you know my mother's cancer is
cured by my good karma
that's a call to prayer right I hope my
mother's conscious sure that's called a
prayer okay now when you do blackmail
Dharma blackmail that's called
dedication okay
if you kill my mom's cancer I will
meditate every day for three hours okay
I dedicate the camera of my practice to
kill my mom's cancer okay that's called
making a deal with the Buddha okay
that's the difference okay
prayer is cheap I hope you kill my mom
okay
that's called prayer dedication is
prayer with Bakshi deal you offer a deal
to Buddha
if you kill my mom I will keep my
meditation for one year okay every day
okay that's called dedication that's the
difference
okay next last question you there's a
prayer that we have that you can use for
the seven ingredients if you have a lot
of time like on Sunday or you have a two
week vacation from your job it's in the
prayer book that we wrote where's that
prayer book can you have a copy can they
still get it there's a prayer book
called the three treasures okay and I
translated the three great books of
Prayer and they're all together okay so
one is called the thousand angels one
thousand angels and if you want to do a
nice slow long seven ingredients in a
retreat cabin for example just use that
book okay that's the traditional book
that's used for the seven ingredients
it's called the thousand angels
of the heaven of bliss of dough sheeter
heaven okay and you have it so don't
complain don't tell me you don't know
where it is it's in the bookstore if you
want the online copy for free you can
have that okay talk to Tim okay and Gina
where's Gina she laid it out is so
beautiful the book is so beautiful very
sexy yeah and I'm very proud of it every
church should have a purple and we have
a beautiful purple thank you for all
right you ready cinema ginger she
[Music]
mentioned egg and buy some yes and shame
on you
[Music]
son I taught song ji-sun I mention
Dhamma honey topa show by the way the
one thing I did do tonight when I taught
meditation that nobody noticed was that
you participated ok you got to say
something and that's a good way to teach
meditation okay so when you teach a CI
or you teach meditation try to find a
way that the students can participate
and they can give their own ideas and
things like that and then they listen
and they don't sleep okay so that's a
big teaching trick or read taught me
that or read it's very good teacher
about that so you know get the students
to find a way that they can participate
okay and then they will learn more okay
all right